kitten과 cat와의 관계는 puppy와 dog가
의미론적 유사한 관계를 갖는다는 것을 말하고 있습니다.
Saying that a kitten is to cat what a
puppy is to a dog is a semantic analogy.
shorter와 short와의 관계는
taller와 tall과의 통사론적 유사한 관계를
갖는다는 말하고 있습니다.
Just like saying that shorter is
to short what taller is to tall
is a syntactic analogy.
embedding factors의 재미있는
요소가 잘 나타납니다.
Here's a fun emergent properties
of those embedding factors.
그것은 수학 연산의 관점과 비슷하게
유사성을 표현할 수 있게 합니다.
They let you express analogies like this
in terms of mathematical operations.
만약, 당신이 좋은 모델이 있다면,
If you have a good model, and
puppy에 대한 vector를 가지고 있고
dog을 빼고
you take the vector for puppy,
subtract the vector for
cat에 대한 vector를 더하면,
다른 vector를 얻게 됩니다.
dog and then add back the vector for
cat, then you get another vector.
만약 imbedding space안에 가장 근접한
어떤 vector를 보면,
If you look for what that vector
is closest to in imbedding space,
그것은 kitten이 될 것입니다.
chances are that it will be kitten.